

# Muhamad Hafiz Bin Abdul Aziz

0176390589 0134061204

hafiz 2006@hotmail.co.uk

#### **SUMMARY**

To apply System Engineer position that currently been offered by your company. Currently working as System Engineer, previously worked as Network Analyst. Furthermore, I'm ready to learn any new things that related to position that I'm applied and ready to give full commitment to task that I've been assigned. To be honest, I'm fast leaner & I can adapt to almost any situation.

You may call me for interview if you would like to know me more.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Systems Engineer (Onsite), Cuscapi (M) Sdn Bhd (former known as Datascan)

Job Size 14 Subang, April 2013 - Present

Worked as On-site System Engineer which is support POS (point of sales) equipment (hardware & software). 2<sup>nd</sup> level field support with customers (KFC, Pizzahut, Nandos, TGIF, Tony Romas etc).

Current Salary: MYR 4000++ (basic MYR 3000 + allowance MYR1000++)

## Jobscope cover workshop & field support

- Fixed various model of POS equipment including Posiflex 6K, 5K and 5K Pro model, Toshiba A-10 model, Partner SE-300 & SP-1000
- Fixed broken POS that had issue with software & hardware, onsite & in workshop
- Fixed another POS equipment such as printer (TRST-A10, PP7000, PP8000, TM-T88II, TM-U220B)
- Need to fix any issue involve on customer site, software related issue like SQL Issue, Windows Issue, Transight Issue, programming
- Remote access to outlet to troubleshoot issue before attend customer site – access remotely using Teamviewer, LogMeIn.
- Re-imaged HDD on site, replaced broken hardware at site such as KDS Exceed 4000, Epic, Bumpbar, motherboard for POS, POS cabling & network cabling
- Fixed software & hardware issue at site
- Replaced broken database for Transight, restore & backup Transight
- Performed 24/7 support for daily standby
- Performed PM for KFC & Pizza Hut Malaysia, also Malaysia Airport Technology Berhad
- Attend for Transight Training for 2 weeks

# Network Analyst, AT&T Worlwide Communication Services

Cyberjaya, Nov 2011 - May 2013

Work as Tier 1 support center. Assists customers from US soil for their T1 Internet services. Managing, isolating and fixing T1 circuit that having issue. Coaching floor tech with process and workflow when they are having trouble. Assists in escalation issue that involve irate customers.

Current Salary: MYR 3000 (basic MYR 2300 + allowance MYR700)

#### Accomplishments

- Promoted as SME (Subject Matter Expert after 5 month work)
- Promoted as Team Lead (9 Month Later)
- Nominated as Best Employee of Month (November 2012)
- Received a lot of KUDOS and commendations both from customers and Service Managers

#### Trainee, Xyratex (M) Sdn. Bhd.

Seremban, Nov 2009 – April 2010 (5 Months)

Assigned in Manufacturing Engineering Department

## Responsibilities and duties:

- Assist in set-up workbench and work status for production
- Assist in Time File studied
- Assist Engineers in project assigned new product & analyst
- Assists to support Production on daily issues
- Assists in provide drawing for Layout, Tool & Jig

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Universiti Teknikal Malaysia Melaka

Bachelor of Electronic Engineering (Computer Engineering)

Degree — 2007 - 2011

# Matriculation (Kolej Matrikulasi Negeri Sembilan)

Physics 2006 - 2007

#### **PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENT**

#### Final Year Project (Degree)

Effect of Wireless Mesh Network on Social Network Activity

 This project was about to study the effect of wireless mesh network on protocols that exist in social network activity. Using Cisco Router WRT610N, mesh network successfully created using 4 routers operate at 5GHz frequency with high throughput results.

# Certificates

- CompTIA Network+ (2009 edition) (ID: COMP001020204038)
- POS Transight Training (CUSCAPI BHD)
- IPC-A-610 Acceptability of Electronics Assemblies Training and Certification
- Silver Award INOTEK 2011 (UTeM)
- Industry Award INOTEK 2011 (UTeM)
- 2nd Runner Up Broadband & Multimedia System Category INOTEK 2011 (UTeM)
- W3 Schools Certified PHP Developer Certificate (MySQL)

#### Contribution

- Paper published Analysis of Lightning-induced Transient in Wireless Communication System
- Design and Setup Wireless Mesh Network test-bed for research

.

#### **SKILLS**

- Advanced skills in troubleshoot windows platform and also computer's hardware – had part-time job during study to fix any kind of computer's issue, hardware & software
- Advanced skill in troubleshoot POS hardware
- Familiar with POS software (Transight) used by F&B Industries like KFC, Pizza Hut, Tony Romas, Nandos etc.
- Advances skills in communicate with customers/peoples
- Advanced skill in using Virtual Desktop Solutions, used VMWare before to install LINUX based OS
- Advanced skill in using Remote Dekstop Services like Teamviewer, RealVNC, UltraVNC – currently still using it
- Familiar with Server OS most POS System using Server OS 2003
- Familiar with ECM, POS System using this ECM system to manage their sales
- Experienced with trouble-ticketing support system AT&T Worldwide Communications & Cuscapi (M) Sdn Bhd using ticketing system to support their customer
- Familiar with Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8 and some of LINUX platforms.
- Familiar with Citrix PS4 and XenApp 6.5
- · Re-imaged HDD using Ghost applications
- Fixed POS equipment's hardware (Toshiba, Posiflex, Partner) including priter, KDS (kitchen display screen)
- Setup SQL between server & client for POS
- Advanced skills in computer networking including using network measurements tools, eg: iX-Chariot, Colasoft, Netstumbler, InSSider, WirelessMON
- Intermediate skill in configuring CISCO routers.
- Familiar with Virtual Private Network (VPN) design and development.
- Proficiency in using digital and analog oscilloscope.
- Intermediate in using Microsoft Office 2007, 2010 (Excel/Word/Publisher/Outlook)
- Intermediate in using Open Office
- Intermediate in using command for Juniper and Cisco routers

#### **REFERENCES**

Upon request.